Mateusz Wilk

Senior Web Developer w BBC

matewilk@gmail.com

Summary

Over my studies on Faculty of Electrical, Electronic, Computer and Control Engineering I have been using many different languages but when I have developed my first Single Site Application in 2008 I fell in love with Web Developement. Since than I have gained solid experience building large business web applications using open source languages like JavaScript, php, and Sql. During my 5+ years of professional work I have been using many MVC based frameworks like Zend, Symfony, ExtJs, Backbone.js libraries – jQuery, raphael, smarty, less and others. Tools like Git, SVG, DbDesigner, WebStorm and many others used in developing modern javascript, html5 OOP solutions. I am working in agile methodology keeping high quality standards even in requirements changing environment. Always keeping-up to up to date trends in web development.

Experience

Senior Web Developer at BBC

grudzie# 2015 - Obecnie (3 mies.)

Web Developer at BBC

marzec 2014 - grudzie# 2015 (1 rok 10 mies.)

Javascript - Backbone.js, Node.js, React.js CSS3 - Sass, Bootstrap, Angular-Material TDD - Jasmine, Mocha, Sinon, Chai BDD - Behat, Continuous Integration - Hudson, Heroku, AWS, Jenkins Yeoman, Bower, Grunt, Vagrant, Selenium, Require.js, Webpack

Software Developer at Arbor Education Partners

lipiec 2013 - luty 2014 (8 mies.)

Web/Javascript Developer at Focus Telecom Polska Sp. z o.o.

wrzesie# 2010 - lipiec 2013 (2 lata 11 mies.)

- Development, modifications and new functionality implementation in Javascript based CRM system (features of CRM system could be seen at: http://www.focustelecom.pl/en/oferta/virtual-crm/) front-end components implementation (creation of ExtJs components extensions) user interface desing usability design front-end wizards for system modules design and implementation data presentation in charts (ExtJs) GUI implementation (forms, controls, grids, panels with custom layouts, combobox templates, custom data views etc.) Application architecture implementation Back-end implementation (also SQL) Implementation, development and full responsibility for mass SMS mailing service for companies
- (http://www.smsmanager.pl/) Technologies: PHP (Zend Framework), Javascript (ExtJs, jQuery), SQL (PostgreSQL)

Programmer Javascript/PHP/SQL at Expanse S.p z o.o.

grudzie# 2009 - wrzesie# 2010 (10 mies.)

- Contribution in developing satellite vehicle monitoring, controll and localization application (introduction to the system can be seen at : www.gps-log.pl) - GUI implementation (Javascript, Ext js, Ajax) - Application architecture implementation (PHP, Zend Framework) - Database design assistance (DbDesigner); - Writing SQL queries and procedures (PostgreSQL);

Web Developer at Freelancer - #ód#

pa#dziernik 2008 - maj 2009 (8 mies.)

- Modification and new web services functionality development with PHP, MySql, html, css, jQuery, Smarty - Implementation from scratch without any framework (own architecture) of website of designing office www.deigie.pl (polish/english) - Implementation and modification of meteorological shop based on prestashop www.stacjemeteo.pl - Realisation homepage of – http://arkadiuszwlodarczyk.com

Software Developer at Freelancer - Hiszpania

kwiecie# 2008 - wrzesie# 2008 (6 mies.)

- ERP system implementation, SQL programming

Analyst at Inoxpa - Spain

wrzesie# 2007 - wrzesie# 2008 (1 rok 1 miesi#c)

- Participation in the implementation of ERP system - Design of information management system in the company - Building workflow diagrams in UML - Enterprise software needs analysis - Analysis of the hardware requirements - Project cost estimate - Share Point Services 3.0 Implementation and server administration Tools: Visual Studio .NET, Microsoft Windows Server 2005, Miscrosoft Web Developer

IT Intern at INOXPA

2007 - 2008 (1 rok)

Courses

Web Developer

BBC

Code Reviews

Continuous Integration

Pair Programming

Behavioral Driven Development

Test Driven Development

HTML5 for Mobile and Web

Microservices

AWS:reInvent 2015

.....

Indywidualny tok nauki

Front-Trends 2013 Conference

meet.js meet ups

backbone.js London meet up

node.js meet up

MongoDB for Node.js Developers

M101JS

Languages

polski (J#zyk ojczysty lub bieg#o## dwuj#zyczna)

angielski (Bieg#o## na poziomie zaawansowanym)

hiszpa#ski (Bieg#o## na poziomie #redniozaawansowanym)

Skills & Expertise

jQuery

Git

HTML 5

CSS3

MVC Architecture

JavaScript

ExtJs

JSON

JavaScriptMVC

Sencha

PHP

SQL

PostgreSQL

MySQL

Linux

Tortoise SVN

NetBeans

Web Development

CRM

Call Centers

Design Patterns

Zend Framework

CSV SmartDraw AJAX VPS

Education

Technical University of Lodz

Master of Science, Technical University of Lodz, Faculty of Electrical, Electronic, Computer and Control

Engineering, 2003 - 2010

Activities and Societies: Microprocessor Autonomous Systems Academic Club - MIPSA

Universitat de Girona

Information and Computer Science, 2008 - 2009

Interests

Javascript IT systems architecture Web developement Internet technologies, IT business solutions

Certifications

MongoDB for Node.js developers

Mateusz Wilk

Senior Web Developer w BBC

matewilk@gmail.com



Contact Mateusz on LinkedIn